Guide to the Michele Zackheim Papers MSS.108
Fales Library and Special Collections
Michele Zackheim Papers
circa 1900-2005
Fales Library and Special Collections
Zackheim, Michele
MSS.108
14 Linear Feet in 24 boxes, a VHS tape in shared housing, 2 computer disks in shared housing, and 31 cassettes in shared housing
2 VHS
1 DVD
33 audiocassettes 31 mini cassettes, 2 audiocassettes
101 3.5" floppy disks
2 Disks in 2 zip disks
Writer and visual artist Michele Zackheim is the author of two novels: Violette's Embrace and Einstein's Daughter: the Search for Lieserl. The Michele Zackheim Papers comprise research materials for the novels, including correspondence, manuscripts, legal documents, publicity material, photographs, books such as biographies and tourist guides, and audio and video cassettes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Michele Zackheim Papers were donated to the Fales Library on December 18, 2000 by Michele Zackheim. An accretion was donated by Michele Zackheim in May of 2018; the accession number associated with the accretion is 2018.084.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Biographical Note
Writer and visual artist, Michele Zackheim is the author of two novels. Violette's Embrace: A Novel (Riverhead Books, 1996), is a fictional biography of the French writer Violette Leduc. Her second novel, Einstein's Daughter: The Search for Lieserl (Penguin Putnam, 1999), follows the mystery of the lost illegitimate daughter of Mileva and Albert Einstein. Zackheim has also worked in the visual arts as a fresco muralist, an installation artist, and a painter. She has received two NEA awards, and has taught at the School of Visual Arts in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The Michele Zackheim Papers are comprised of research material, correspondence, manuscripts, legal documents, publicity material, photographs, audio and video cassettes. The research materials include a copy of August Forel's "Die Frage Sexuelle" with manuscript annotations by Mileva Maric, which was unearthed during one of Zackheim's visits to Serbia. Also included are research materials from various archival collections and duplicates of many of the legal documents related to Evelyn Einstein's lawsuit against the Einstein Family Correspondence Trust. The collection also contains source materials such as books including biographies, auction catalogs, and tours guides that focus on the life of Albert Einstein that were used to help write Zackheim's second novel, Einstein's Daughter: The Search for Lieserl, a biography of Einstein's illegitimate daughter.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in five series that have been further arranged in five subseries. The contents of each series or subseries are arranged alphabetically or chronologically. The series and subseries arrangement of the records is as follows:
SERIES I: Leduc
Subseries A: Research
Subseries B: Manuscripts
Subseries C: Legal
Subseries D: Correspondence
Subseries E: Publicity
Subseries F: Media
Subseries G: Photographs
Subseries H: Miscellaneous
SERIES II: New Yorker Assignments
Subseries A: Research
Subseries B: Manuscripts
Subseries C: Correspondence
Subseries D: Miscellaneous
SERIES III: Einstein
Subseries A: Research
Subseries B: Manuscripts
Subseries C: Legal Documents
Subseries D: Correspondence
Subseries E: Publicity
Subseries F: Media
Subseries G: Photographs
Subseries H: Administrative
Subseries I: Miscellaneous SERIES IV: Albert Einstein Family Correspondence Trust
Subseries A: Legal Documents
Subseries B: Correspondence
Subseries C: Miscellaneous
SERIES V: Miscellaneous writing assignments and projects
Subseries A: Writings
Subseries B: Visual Arts
Subseries C: Miscellaneous
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact NYU Special Collections (special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596) with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact NYU Special Collections (special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596) with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Magnetic disks.; Picture postcards.; Page proofs.; Black-and-white photographs.; Faxes.; Printed ephemera.; Videocassettes.; Correspondence.; Legal documents.; Books.; Black-and-white negatives.; Birth certificates.; Physicists -- Biography; Illegitimate children |v Biography.; Pamphlets.; Serbia.; Clippings (information artifacts); Audiocassettes.; Death certificates.; Photocopies.; Color negatives.; Manuscripts for publication.; Color prints (photographs); Biography.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955; Einstein, Evelyn; Einstein, Lieserl, 1902-; Einstein-Maric, Mileva, 1875-1948; Leduc, Violette, 1907-1972; Cole, Mary, 1790-1812
- Series I: Leduc
  Scope and Content note
  Contains materials related to the production of Zackheim's first novel, Violette's Embrace, a fictional biography of Violette Leduc. Organized in five subseries.
  - Subseries A: Research
    Scope and Contents note
    Zackheim's research files for for Violette's Embrace, arranged alphabetically by author, where applicable, or subject. Includes correspondence and notes.
    - Abbott, H.P.- Diary Fiction, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
    - Algren, Nelson, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
    - Atlas, James- "Holmes on the Case", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
    - Barbellion, W.N.P.- "Journal of a Disappointed Man", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 4)
    - Beauty, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 5)
    - Beauvoir, Simone de., undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 6)
    - Bibliography, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 7)
    - Bibliotheque Nationale, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 8)
    - Book Search, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 9)
    - Bree, Germaine, "Narcissus Absconditus", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 10)
    - Bree, Germaine- Women Writers in France, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 11)
    - Bree, Germaine, and Guiton, Margaret- "An Age of Affliction", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 12)
    - Bruss, Elizabeth- "Autobiographical Acts", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 13)
    - Bunke, Carolyn 'Report from Paris", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 14)
    - Cafe Flore, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 15)
    - Camus, Albert, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 16)
    - Cocteau, Jean, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 17)
    - Copy Card, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 18)
    - Courtivron, Isabelle de- "Violette Leduc", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 19)
    - Courtivron, Isabelle de- "Violette Leduc", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 20)
    - Courtivron, Isabelle de- "Violette Leduc's A'Affamee", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 21)
    - Elbaz, Robert- "The Changing Nature of the Self", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 22)
    - Equipment, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 23)
    - Esslin, Martin- "The Theatre of the Absurd", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 24)
    - Evans, Martha- "Masks of Tradition", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 25)
    - Faulkner, William- "A Rose for Emily", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 26)
    - Flanner, Janet (Genet), undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 27)
    - Flanner, Janet (Genet), undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 28)
    - Friends of Leduc, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 29)
    - Funding research, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 30)
    - Genet, Jean, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 31)
    - Gide, Andre, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 32)
    - Housing in Paris, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 33)
    - Interview notes, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 34)
    - Jones, Ann R. "Writing the Body", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 35)
    - Leduc, Violette- Articles for voyage, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 36)
    - Leduc, Violette-Brigitte Bardot, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 37)
    - Leduc, Violette- clippings, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 38)
    - Leduc, Violette- death certificate, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 39)
    - Leduc, Violette- letters to Simone de Beauvoir, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 40)
    - Leduc, Violette- list of U.S. periodical publications, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 41)
    - Leduc, Violette- "My Mother", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 42)
    - Leduc, Violette- Reviews, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 43)
    - Literary agents, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 44)
    - Lottman, Herbert- "Literary Life in Paris", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 45)
    - Map- hand drawn, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 46)
    - Messages, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 47)
    - "I am my Own Heroine" - Elaine Marks, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 48)
    - Matthews and Reader- "Autobiography, Biography, and the Novel"., undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 49)
    - Memo book, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 50)
    - Millett, Kate- "Sita", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 51)
    - Monnier, Adrienne- "Joyce's Ulysses and the French Public", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 52)
    - Murchland, Bernard- "The Advent of Alienation", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 53)
    - National Coalition of Independent Scholars, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 54)
    - Notes, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 55)
    - Orenstein, Gloria F. "La Poete Mandite", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 56)
    - Peyre, Henri- "French Novelists of Today", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 57)
    - Plantine, Therese, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 58)
    - Pringle, Lauren H. - "Annotated and Indexed Calendar of de Beauvoir's Letters to Nelson Algren, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 59)
    - Psychology, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 60)
    - Quotatations, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 61)
    - Respant, Michele - "Femme/ange, Femme/monstre", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 62)
    - "Revealing Lives", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 63)
    - Sachs, Maurice, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 64)
    - Schor, Naomi- "Breaking the Chain", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 65)
    - Selected bibliography, undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 66)
    - Shapiro, Stephen- "The Dark Continent of Literature", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 67)
    - Smith, Sidonie- "A Poetics of Women's Autobiography", undated; 31142040610647 (Box 1A, Folder 68)
    - Tamargout, Serge, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 69)
    - Triolet, Elsa, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 70)
    - "Twentieth Century French Fiction", undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 71)
    - Unused Quotations, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 72)
    - Vallorz, Paulo, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 73)
    - Vinlar, St. Anne Marguerite, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 74)
    - Weintraub, Karl J. "The Value of the Individual", undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 75)
    - Wilson, Edmund, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 76)
    - 'Women and Language in Literature and Society", undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 77)
    - Women and philanthropy, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 78)
    - Women writers in transition, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 79)
    - "Women writers talking", undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 80)
    - Yalom, Marilyn- "They Remember Maman", undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 81)
    - Research card file, A-N, undated (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_88cafac897ceb0576adcc880166a9b36)
    - Research card file, O-Z, undated (Box 14, Folder data_value_missing_2b80e7a4cc6754a53911bf98433e3622)
    - Audio micro-cassettes, undated (Box 23)
  - Subseries B: Manuscripts
    Manuscripts and drafts of Violette's Embrace.
    - Early Notes, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 82)
    - Notes for first draft, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 83)
    - First draft, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 84)
    - First TS- Titled "Words on Loan", undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 85)
    - "Words on Loan"- title page and art, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 86)
    - Pieces taken from manuscript, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 87)
    - Typeset manuscript (1/3), undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 88)
    - Typeset manuscript (1/3), undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 89)
    - Typeset manuscript (1/3), undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 90)
    - Manuscript errors, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 91)
    - Manuscript- Kathy Anderson's notes on, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 92)
    - First galley with corrections (1/2), undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 93)
    - First galley with corrections (1/2), undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 94)
    - Pages from first galley- with revisions, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 95)
    - Corrected proof, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 96)
  - Subseries C: Legal Documents
    Legal documents and release forms securing permission to quote from various sources related to Violette's Embrace.
    - Legal copyright information, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 97)
    - List of Citations, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 98)
    - Permissions to quote 1/2, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 99)
    - Permissions to quote 2/2, undated; 31142042240104 (Box 1B, Folder 100)
  - Subseries D: Correspondence
    Correspondence between Zackheim and a range of correspondents. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name.
    - Anderson, Kathy, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 101)
    - Benstock, Shari, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 102)
    - Brooks, Christine, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 103)
    - Burk, Craig, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 104)
    - Ceccatty, Rene de, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 105)
    - Clark, Tina, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 106)
    - Cone, Candace, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 107)
    - Connell, Stella, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 108)
    - Depland, Daniel, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 109)
    - Ehrlich, Gretel, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 110)
    - Elhanani, Iris, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 111)
    - Faibish, Roy, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 112)
    - Fleissig, Josef, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 113)
    - Funk, Allison, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 114)
    - Grau, Julie, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 115)
    - Gross, Amy, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 116)
    - Heckin Group Foundation, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 117)
    - Hoekstra, Froukje, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 118)
    - Howard, Richard, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 119)
    - Jackson, Donald, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 120)
    - Jacobson, Rachel, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 121)
    - Jansiti, Carlo, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 122)
    - Jardine, Anna, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 123)
    - Lenstrem-Sheedy, Bob, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 124)
    - Lerner, Betsy, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 125)
    - LewAllen, Arlene, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 126)
    - Lottman, Herbert, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 127)
    - Marks, Elaine, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 128)
    - Markson, Elaine, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 129)
    - Maurel, Marcelle, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 130)
    - Miller, Laura, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 131)
    - Millett, Kate, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 132)
    - Ostashezky, Luba, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 133)
    - Publishers (1/2), undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 134)
    - Publishers (1/2), undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 135)
    - Readers' Responses, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 136)
    - Recordon, Claire, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 137)
    - Reiger, Bill, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 138)
    - Reighard, Jessica, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 139)
    - Sartori, Eva, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 140)
    - Shapiro, Gerald, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 141)
    - Sifton, Elizabeth, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 142)
    - Spayde, John, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 143)
    - Tamagnot, Serge, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 144)
    - Veron, Marianne, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 145)
    - Wan, Nicole, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 146)
    - Werhane, Kathryn, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 147)
    - Wright, Ellen, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 148)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 149)
    - Partial name / unidentified, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 150)
  - Subseries E: Publicity
    Includes publicity materials for readings, mailings and other promotions. Arranged alphabetically by material.
    - Barnes and Noble Reading, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 151)
    - Blurbs, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 152)
    - Book Covers, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 153)
    - Book Jackets, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 154)
    - Book Pages, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 155)
    - Complementary Book Mailing List, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 156)
    - Daedalus Books, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 157)
    - Flyers / Announcements, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 158)
    - General, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 159)
    - Leduc Reading, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 160)
    - Leduc Summary, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 161)
    - News Clippings, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 162)
    - Putnam Announcement, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 163)
    - Putnam Catalogue, Spring/Summer 1996; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 164)
    - Review Mailing List, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 165)
  - Subseries G: Photos
    Photographic materials from files for Violette's Embrace.
    - Negatives, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 166)
    - Photocopied photos, general, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 167)
    - Photocopied photos, Leduc, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 168)
    - Photographs, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 169)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 12)
    - Photograph of Violette Leduc, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Subseries H: Miscellaneous
    Miscellaneous materials from files for Violette's Embrace.
    - Addresses, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 170)
    - F.U.S.A.C., undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 171)
    - Play, first draft, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Floppy disks (Box 23)
- Series II: New Yorker Assignments
  Comprised of research, manuscripts and correspondence related to two proposed articles on the Einstein family for The New Yorker (neither of which was published): one on Lieserl Einstein, the subject of Einstein's Daughter, and one on the legal battles of Evelyn Einstein, with whom Zackheim struck up a friendship during her research on the family. Arranged in four subseries.
  - Subseries A: Research
    Research materials specifically related to the New Yorker assignments. Arranged alphabetically by author, where applicable, or by subject.
    - Request for Assistance, September 5, 1995, 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 1)
    - Inquiry re: Einstein Letter, March 12, 1996, 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Manuscripts
    Drafts and proposals for New Yorker assignments on Lieserl ("Einstein's Daughter") and Evelyn Einstein. Arranged by title and then by loose chronology.
    - "Einstein's Daughter," First Draft, June 28, 1995, 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 3)
    - "Einstein's Daughter," early Drafts, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 4)
    - Einstein's Daughter," corrected draft, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 5)
    - "Einstein's Daughter," draft, March 28, 1996, 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 6)
    - "Einstein's Daughter," corrected draft, April 26, 1996, 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 7)
    - "Evelyn Einstein: A Profile", undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 8)
    - "The Misfortune of Evelyn Einstein"-Proposal, November 20, 1996, 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 9)
    - "The Misfortune of Evelyn Einstein", undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 10)
    - "The Missed Fortunes of Evelyn Einstein", undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 11)
    - "A Profile of Evelyn Einstein"-Proposal, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 12)
    - Untitled manuscript page, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 13)
  - Subseries C: Correspondence
    Correspondence with Zackheim's agent, staff and editors of the New Yorker. For the bulk of Zackheim's correspondence related to Einstein see series III subseries D.
    - Anderson, Kathleen, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 14)
    - Dokmanovic, Marija, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 15)
    - Garrison, Deborah, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 16)
  - Subseries D: Miscellaneous
    Other materials related to the New Yorker assignments that consist of expense accounting and invoices.
    - Expenses, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 17)
    - Invoices, undated; 31142042240112 (Box 1C, Folder 18)
- Series III: Einstein
  Contains materials related to the production of Zackheim's second novel, Einstein's Daughter: The Search for Lieserl, a biography of Einstein's illegitimate daughter, conceived out of wedlock when Einstein and Mileva Maric were students at Zurich Polytechnic Institute. These files were collected over the five year period in which Zackheim investigated the possible fates of Lieserl. Organized into nine subseries.
  - Subseries A: Research
    Contains Michele Zackheim's research files that include notes, correspondence, books such as biographies and tourist guides, and photographs for Einstein's Daughter. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by author when relevant and subject with the exception of Michele Zackheim's note card file and research binders, which can be found at the end of the subseries. Research Binder # 4 consisting of negatives, contact sheets, and photographs was removed and transferred to subseries G, box 11.
    - Adelson, Alan, undated; 31142040610654 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Adoption, undated; 31142040610654 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Austria-Serbian Orthodox Church, undated; 31142040610654 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bala Family-Death Certificate, undated; 31142040610654 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Barbara Deming Memorial Fund Application, undated; 31142040610654 (Box 2, Folder 4a)
    - Beck, Anna, undated; 31142040610654 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Berlin Maps, undated; 31142040610654 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Berlin Trip, undated; 31142040610654 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Berlin Archives, undated; 31142040610654 (Box 2, Folder 8)